intmath.com 2013-05-23

# Privacy Policy

Interactive Mathematics does not sell or give away your personal information, ever. Your right to privacy is paramount.

The information that you provide (when leaving a comment or asking a question) stays with Interactive Mathematics. 

## Summary of Information Collected & Used 

IntMath may keep some, or possibly all, of the following information about visitors:

### All visitors 

Any information kept on general visitors is anonymous. That is, no names or emails or any other personally identifying information is known, or kept in relation to this class of information (anonymous and passive). 

  1. Pages visited in IntMath and squareCircleZ blog (via server logs)
  2. External referer site (where visitors came from)
  3. Activity while on certain pages (to improve usability and value of pages) 

This information is used only to improve the layout and usability of the sites, and a balance between effectiveness of advertising and usefulness of the articles.

The data logs, including Google Analytics information, are never shared with any other party, and never will be.

### IntMath Newsletter Subscribers 

The following personal information is kept to facilitate functioning of the Newsletter:

  1. Name (as provided by the user)
  2. Email address
  3. Country (as determined from IP address of the computer used by the subscriber)
  4. Type of visitor (either student, teacher, parent, retired) via self-nomination 
  5. Any comments, requests or suggestions made by the user when subscribing, or subsequently

This information is used to continuously improve the usefulness of the Newsletter to subscribers.

We also take note of the most popular stories in each Newsletter, via clicks to those stories, to evaluate the interest level of different types of articles with the aim of continuous improvement. 

The Newsletter subscribers list has never been shared with any other party, and never will be. 

## Email Privacy

Your email address is never displayed on Interactive Mathematics or on the associated [squareCircleZ](http://www.intmath.com/blog/) blog. Everyone hates spam!

## Cookies

Sometimes cookies are placed on your computer to improve the functionality of the site. A cookie is a small text file that sits in your browser's cache. For example, Interactive Mathematics conducts a poll from time to time and a cookie is used to remember your voting status (voted already, or not voted yet). These cookies will **not** store personal information about you and will **not** be used in a malacious way. They do not track where you've been on other sites.

The poll cookie is a persistent cookie, which means it will stay on your computer for a certain amount of time, then disappear.

There is also a mobile device cookie, which is set when visitors choose how to view the site with their mobile device (either mobile version or full version). 

## Third-party Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit this website. These companies may use information ( **not** including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites, including search engines, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. This "behavioral advertisitng" is used by Google Adsense, which is used throughout the sites. 

If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/faq).

## Privacy policies of linked sites

Throughout IntMath and squareCircleZ there are links to other sites, including sponsored links, independent of IntMath. These sites will have their own Privacy Policies and users are encouraged to read those policies before sharing personal information on those sites. 

## Server hosting company's Privacy Policy 

IntMath is hosted on WiredTree servers in Chicago, USA. We strictly abide by their [Terms of Service](http://www.wiredtree.com/legal/tos.php) statement on Spam, which says in part:

> ### SPAM and Unsolicited Commercial Email (UCE)
> 
> WiredTree takes a zero tolerance approach to the sending of Unsolicited Commercial Email (UCE) or spam over our network. Very simply this means that customers of WiredTree may not use or permit others to use our network to transact in UCE. Clients of WiredTree may not host, or permit hosting of, sites or information that is advertised by UCE from other networks. 

## Questions or Concerns

Please use the [Comments](http://www.intmath.com/help/comments.php) facility to raise any concerns you may have about your privacy on Interactive Mathematics.

Didn't find what you are looking for on this page? Try **search** :

### Online Algebra Solver

This algebra solver can solve a wide range of math problems. (Please be patient while it loads.)

Go to: [Online algebra solver](http://www.intmath.com/help/problem-solver.php)

### Ready for a break?

Play a [math game](http://www.intmath.com/games/games.php?a=3).

(Well, not really a math game, but each game was made using math...)

### The IntMath Newsletter

Sign up for the free **IntMath Newsletter**. Get math study tips, information, news and updates each fortnight. Join thousands of satisfied students, teachers and parents!

### Share IntMath!

### Short URL for this Page

Save typing! You can use this URL to reach this page:

### Math Lessons on DVD

Easy to understand math lessons on DVD. See samples before you commit.

More info: [Math videos](http://www.intmath.com/help/math-videos/?topic=math)
